<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Assignment &#8211; lili enseling</title>
	<atom:link href="https://lenseling.github.io//project-type/assignment/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://lenseling.github.io//</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 06:26:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.3.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://lenseling.github.io//wp-content/uploads/2023/11/Screenshot-2023-11-02-012459-50x50.png</url>
	<title>Assignment &#8211; lili enseling</title>
	<link>https://lenseling.github.io//</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Last Frontiers: HTML and CSS </title>
		<link>https://lenseling.github.io//portfolio/last-frontiers-html-and-css/</link>
					<comments>https://lenseling.github.io//portfolio/last-frontiers-html-and-css/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[liliyang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 04:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lenseling.github.io//?post_type=jetpack-portfolio#038;p=80</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction In this project, I tackled the challenge of making a user-friendly and responsive website, emphasizing HTML and CSS execution. Figma Wireframe lastfrontiers.com Process I established a strong foundation through wireframing and comprehensive color layout, and adopted a mobile-first approach, optimizing for desktop with media queries. I also incorporated embedded videos and audio clips to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Introduction</h4>



<p>In this project, I tackled the challenge of making a user-friendly and responsive website, emphasizing HTML and CSS execution.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-3 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow">
<p><a href="https://www.figma.com/file/7Hmb6vLz3NQUFJkodOJWDL/enseling_lili_p1?type=design&amp;t=vRdrqohbaQYLcPJE-6" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.figma.com/file/7Hmb6vLz3NQUFJkodOJWDL/enseling_lili_p1?type=design&amp;t=vRdrqohbaQYLcPJE-6">Figma Wireframe</a></p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow">
<p><a href="https://lastfrontiers.000webhostapp.com/" data-type="link" data-id="https://lastfrontiers.000webhostapp.com/">lastfrontiers.com</a></p>
</div>
</div>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Process</h4>



<p>I established a strong foundation through wireframing and comprehensive color layout, and adopted a mobile-first approach, optimizing for desktop with media queries. I also incorporated embedded videos and audio clips to enhance the user experience, and I experimented with new CSS techniques to elevate the site&#8217;s aesthetics and usability. </p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h4>



<p>This project showcases my commitment to mastering HTML and CSS best practices, adaptability in embracing new coding techniques, and dedication to delivering a user-friendly, professionally structured, and visually appealing website, marking a significant milestone in my web development journey.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lenseling.github.io//portfolio/last-frontiers-html-and-css/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UI/UX Design for a Fashion Article</title>
		<link>https://lenseling.github.io//portfolio/mejo-187-ui-ux-project/</link>
					<comments>https://lenseling.github.io//portfolio/mejo-187-ui-ux-project/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[liliyang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 03:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lenseling.github.io//?post_type=jetpack-portfolio#038;p=64</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction In this project, I collaborated with AI to create a website focusing on one of five specified topics. The website included a 500-word article, multimedia elements such as images, audio, and video, and featured at least one interactive component. Figma Prototype &#8211; Web Figma Prototype &#8211; Mobile Target Audience My target audience for the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Introduction</h4>



<p>In this project, I collaborated with AI to create a website focusing on one of five specified topics. The website included a 500-word article, multimedia elements such as images, audio, and video, and featured at least one interactive component.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns is-layout-flex wp-container-6 wp-block-columns-is-layout-flex">
<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://www.figma.com/proto/7Hmb6vLz3NQUFJkodOJWDL/enseling_lili_p1?page-id=1709%3A757&amp;type=design&amp;node-id=1762-343&amp;viewport=47%2C228%2C0.31&amp;t=JjChW1OJ6pfALRLc-1&amp;scaling=contain&amp;starting-point-node-id=1762%3A343&amp;mode=design" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.figma.com/proto/7Hmb6vLz3NQUFJkodOJWDL/enseling_lili_p1?page-id=1709%3A757&amp;type=design&amp;node-id=1762-343&amp;viewport=47%2C228%2C0.31&amp;t=JjChW1OJ6pfALRLc-1&amp;scaling=contain&amp;starting-point-node-id=1762%3A343&amp;mode=design">Figma Prototype &#8211; Web</a></p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column is-layout-flow wp-block-column-is-layout-flow">
<p class="has-text-align-center"><a href="https://www.figma.com/proto/7Hmb6vLz3NQUFJkodOJWDL/enseling_lili_p1?page-id=1762%3A205&amp;type=design&amp;node-id=1762-206&amp;viewport=612%2C253%2C0.44&amp;t=R5nKSrOT4f5kZVaI-1&amp;scaling=scale-down&amp;starting-point-node-id=1762%3A206&amp;mode=design" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.figma.com/proto/7Hmb6vLz3NQUFJkodOJWDL/enseling_lili_p1?page-id=1762%3A205&amp;type=design&amp;node-id=1762-206&amp;viewport=612%2C253%2C0.44&amp;t=R5nKSrOT4f5kZVaI-1&amp;scaling=scale-down&amp;starting-point-node-id=1762%3A206&amp;mode=design">Figma Prototype &#8211; Mobile</a></p>
</div>
</div>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Target Audience</h4>



<p>My target audience for the website is primarily teenage to middle-aged women interested in women&#8217;s fashion and fashion history. These include fashion enthusiasts, trend-followers, and those with an appreciation for the evolution of women&#8217;s fashion over time. To captivate my audience effectively, the web design focuses on a sleek, simple user interface that places a strong emphasis on images and key quotes. Bold and striking visuals relating to fashion will be prominently featured to engage the audience&#8217;s sense of style and aesthetics. Considering the demographic of my audience, the website will be designed to be mobile-friendly as the primary access point, however desktop should also be accessible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The competition primarily includes other online fashion journals, magazines, and blogs that cater to fashion enthusiasts. The website design will aim to stand out through its minimalist yet striking visual style and unique interactive features.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Design</h4>



<p>The design aligns with the themes of innovation and modernization of fashion. Minimalism will be the central design philosophy, as it not only reflects current fashion trends but also allows the content and photography to shine. The title and quotation fonts are a serif font, reminiscent of a fashion magazine cover, with key words emphasized by color differences. The chosen AI-generated centerpiece is a graphic representation of women in the fashion industry. Its contemporary style aligns with the theme of innovation, and the subject resembles current fashion trends.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The interactive timeline is a key feature that serves to enhance the storytelling experience. It allows users to visualize the chronological order of the main impacts of the women featured in the article, as well as the visual differences in styles from the photographs. This feature helps users understand the evolution of fashion over time and appreciate the contributions of these remarkable women in a more engaging and informative way.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h4>



<p>In summary, the web design for the “Four Trailblazing Women in the World of Fashion” article is tailored to its audience&#8217;s interests and preferences, featuring a sleek and mobile-friendly interface, bold visuals, minimalist design, and interactive elements that aid in storytelling and understanding the evolution of fashion.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lenseling.github.io//portfolio/mejo-187-ui-ux-project/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quickly Website Redesign</title>
		<link>https://lenseling.github.io//portfolio/quickly-site-redesign/</link>
					<comments>https://lenseling.github.io//portfolio/quickly-site-redesign/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[liliyang]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 03:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<guid isPermaLink="false">https://lenseling.github.io//?post_type=jetpack-portfolio#038;p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Introduction In this project, I recreated an existing website in Figma, addressing key pain points and making at least three design improvements. I provided two views of the site, allowing navigation between them using prototyping, and included both mobile and desktop versions for a comprehensive redesign. Changes The main changes are:]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Introduction</h4>



<p>In this project, I recreated an <a href="https://www.quicklychapelhill.com/" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.quicklychapelhill.com/">existing website</a> in Figma, addressing key pain points and making at least three design improvements. I provided two views of the site, allowing navigation between them using prototyping, and included both mobile and desktop versions for a comprehensive redesign.</p>



<h4 class="wp-block-heading">Changes</h4>



<p>The main changes are:</p>



<ul>
<li>Removed carousel, changed it into a still background with text overlay</li>



<li>Added boxes to menu items to add color contrast</li>



<li>Moved button from Specials page to home page</li>



<li>Used actual text for the specials rather than an image for accessibility</li>



<li>Added black stroke to text for better contrast</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://lenseling.github.io//portfolio/quickly-site-redesign/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
